# Srivas Chennu

21 Watts Avenue Rochester ME1 1RX +44 7828 90 66 92 srivas@gmail.com



#### **Profile**

I specialise in translating the latest machine learning and statistical inference methods into scalable real-world applications in industry and academia. I have 14+ years of R&D experience, and a background in computer science. My research has been featured by the BBC, Wired Magazine, New Scientist and Discovery Channel. I have worked as a consultant and as a software engineer.

## **Employment**

Senior ML Scientist Apple, UK 2019-present

Developed large-scale deep learning and gradient boosting models for behavioural prediction

Designed and deployed adaptive reinforcement learning based on probabilistic statistical inference

**Assistant Professor** University of Kent, UK 2016-2019

Led health care AI project to predict biomarkers of consciousness from time series data

Senior Research Associate University of Cambridge, UK 2010-2016

Developed statistical, ML and time series models for healthcare technology applications in neurology

Visiting Researcher The Alan Turing Institute, UK 2018

Member of Technical Staff **Oracle Corporation, India** 2002-2004

• Software engineer in the Oracle Reports team, a part of Oracle's Internet Application Server platform

#### **Academic Achievements**

Co-author of 50+ peer-reviewed publications in academic journals; h-index of 26 (as of 2022) Research career spanning academia (University of Cambridge, Kent) and industry (Apple)

#### **Consulting**

# DataTiger (Acquired by Apple in 2018)

2018

Applied ensemble machine learning for predicting customer behaviour

Rsrchxchange 2017

- Developed latent factor models with Apache Spark to power customisation of user experience
- · Built neural network-based natural language processor with Spacy for content similarity analysis

#### **Education**

PhD in Computer Science	University of Kent, Canterbury, UK	2006-2009
MSc in Information and	Hamburg University of Technology	2004-2006
Communication Systems	Hamburg, Germany	
BEng in Computer Science and	Visveswaraiah Technological University	1998-2002
Engineering	Bangalore, India	

### Research and Technical Skills

- Big Data Modelling, Machine Learning
- Parametric, Non-parametric and Bayesian Statistics Applied Artificial Intelligence
- · Data Science and Visualisation
- Signal Processing and Time Series Analysis
- Graph Theory and Network Analysis
- **Tools**: tensorflow, pytorch, pyro, scipy, pandas
- Deep Neural Networks
- · Research Methods in Neuroscience
- · Computer Networking and Security
- · Operating Systems
- Languages: Python, JAVA, C++, C